Capitol Hill Symphony Society 080
People's Archive, MLK Library
Capitol Hill Symphony Society Collection
1962-1965
People's Archive, MLK Library
080
0.25 Linear feet
1 Boxes
Arrangement
Processed without series.
Biographical / Historical
The Capitol Hill Symphony Society was established on January 30, 1964 at St. Mark's Episcopal Church in Washington, D.C. The Society was created "for the purpose of providing 'support for musical activities in the city of Washington, particularly…Capitol Hill'" and served as the non-profit organization behind the newly founded Capitol Hill Symphony Orchestra. Musical Director Victor King led the racially-integrated Orchestra, which was initially made up of approximately 90 volunteers. The concept for the Society was born out of the Gault String Ensemble, which was incorporated into the Capitol Hill Symphony Society. The Orchestra's debut concert was held on March 8, 1964 at St. Mark's (3rd and A Street, SE). It is unclear exactly how long the organization existed, though the latest mention of the Capitol Hill Symphony Orchestra in the Washington Star was from 1967. The Capitol Hill Symphony Orchestra should not be confused with the Capitol City Symphony Orchestra (formerly the Georgetown Symphony Orchestra).
Custodial History
Arnold Taylor, a member of the Capitol Hill Symphony Society, donated the collection to the library in 1995.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of correspondence, memos, by-laws, photographs, programs, meeting minutes, and press releases related to the Capitol Hill Symphony Society. The majority of the materials were created in 1964, although the dates range from 1962 to 1965.
Music; Societies and clubs; Minutes (Records); Organizational Records; Photographs; Correspondence
- Series 1
  - By-Laws, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Capitol Hill News", February-March 1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Capitol Hill News", December 1964-January 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Capitol Spotlight", January 24 1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Minutes - First Meeting, January 30 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Member List, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Memoranda, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Musicians Emergency Fund, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Photographs (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Photographs - Ensemble Performances - Hitchcock Hall of St. Elizabeths Hospital, March 1964 (Item 1)
    - Photographs - Ensemble Performances - Bassists James Moore and Nathaneal Turner - Hitchcock Hall of St. Elizabeth's Hospital, March 1964 (Item 2)
    - Photographs - Ensemble Performances - Practice at Lutheran Church of Reformation, March 1964 (Item 3)
    - Photographs - Ensemble Performances - St. Mark's Episcopal Church - Carroll Mattoon singing, March 8 1964 (Item 4)
    - Photographs - Ensemble Performances - Youth Practicing - St. Mark's Parish Hall, May 1 1964 (Item 5)
    - Photographs - Ensemble Performances - Practice - St. Mark's Parish Hall, May 1 1964 (Item 6)
    - Photographs - Ensemble Performances - Practice - Andrew White - St. Mark's Parish Hall - 3rd and A Streets SE, May 1 1964 (Item 7)
    - Photographs - Ensemble Performances - Practice - William Vosburgh - St. Mark's Parish Hall - 3rd and A Streets SE, May 1 1964 (Item 8)
    - Photographs - Ensemble Performances - Practice - Cynthia Ann Powell and Dr. Victor King - St. Mark's Parish Hall - 3rd and A Streets SE, May 17 1964 (Item 9)
  - Photographs (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Photographs - Individuals - Carroll Mattoon and William Vosburgh, February 25 1964 (Item 1)
    - Photographs - Individuals - Carroll Mattoon - Soprano (2 copies), March 1964 (Item 2)
    - Photographs - Individuals - William Vosburgh - Concert Master, March 1964 (Item 3)
    - Photographs - Individuals - Cynthia Ann Powell - Pianist, May 1964 (Item 4)
    - Photographs - Individuals - Billy White - Associate Conductor, May 1 1964 (Item 5)
    - Photographs - Individuals - Anitra Earle and Billy White, May 1 1964 (Item 6)
    - Photographs - Individuals - Jacqueline Foreman - Bass Clarinet, May 1 1964 (Item 7)
    - Photographs - Individuals - Lyman McCrary - Pianist, May 1 1964 (Item 8)
    - Photographs - Individuals - Lyman McCrary - Librarian of Capitol Hill Symphony Orchestra, May 1 1964 (Item 9)
    - Photographs - Individuals - Cynthia Ann Powell, Pianist, May 17 1964 (Item 10)
  - Press Releases, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Programs, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Recreational Therapy Branch Programs, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Rules and Policies, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Saint Elizabeths Reporter", August 1964 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Washington Star Sunday Magazine", May 10 1964 (Box 1, Folder 17)